尽管得花点时间来解释
It took me a while to figure out
但这是了解你们巴尼叔叔的关键
but the key to understanding your Uncle Barney is this.
你不爽时 抓都抓不住他
When times are hard, it's impossible to keep him around.
比如当莉莉阿姨 和马修叔叔分手的时候
Like when your aunt Lily and Uncle Marshall were broken up.
聊什么呢
Hey. What are you guys talking about?
- 莉莉... - 我得走了
- Lily. - I got to go.
你开心的时候 他就苍蝇一样赶的赶不走
But when times are good, it's impossible to get rid of him.
伙计们干吗呢
What are you guys doing?
我们刚商量好 怎么给马修办单身汉派对
We just finished planning Marshall's bachelor party.
讨论还没开始吧 我们来谈谈具体流程
Good, you haven't started yet. Let's talk logistics.
莉莉有给你禁令?
Now, have you laid out ground rules with Lily?
什么地方能摸 什么地方不能摸或者被摸?
Where you are or aren't allowed to touch or be touched?
在泰德身上演示一下
Show me on Ted.
我们不打算要脱衣舞娘
Actually, we're, uh, we're thinking of skipping the strippers.
你们...要举行 没有脱衣舞的派对
You... you want to have a party without strippers.
我不得不说 最糟糕的事情是
This was the worse thing I could have said.
巴尼叔叔喜欢胡搞单身汉派对
You see, uncle Barney loved cooking up bachelor parties.
并且总是一模一样的胡搞
And it was always the same recipe.
狭窄的旅馆房间
You start with a slightly cramped hotel suite.
椅子围成一圈
Arrange the chairs in a circle...
老友团团而坐
Fill them with your closest friends.
温度直达90度 (注:这里是华氏温度 大致等于32℃)
Turn the heat up to about 90.
吞云又吐雾
Pump in a metric ton of cigar smoke.
接着  房间中央 舞女开始妖娆
And then, right in the middle of the room, you throw in a girl.
但并非美女
But not a beautiful girl--
就算她曾是个美女 那也是在她两次怀孕
no, if this girl was ever beautiful, it was two kids,
三次纹身  一次吸毒之前
three tattoos and one pesky substance abuse problem ago.
你们当中谁是斯图尔特 (新郎)
Which one of you is Stuart?
不用了  我没打算要这样
Please, I really don't want to do this.
闭嘴  小心别咬到舌头
Shut up, put in your mouth guard.
她接下来所做的 让新郎蒙羞
Then she proceeds to do things that demean the groom,
让她自己蒙羞 让整个人类为之蒙羞
herself and really, the entire human race.
真恶心
Disgusting.
太恐怖了
Ah, horrifying.
- 经典 - 拜托  不  不
- Classic. - Oh, please, please, no, no.
我可不想那样的事发生在我身上
I don't want anything like that happening to me.
斯途尔特至今 仍对那个晚上耿耿于怀
Stuart's still trying to forget that night.
这是我的派对 我不要脱衣舞娘
It's my bachelor party. We're not having strippers.
他还以为他是柳下惠
Oh, he thinks he has a sain it.
脱衣舞万岁
So, strippers it is!
现在  告诉我地点 我来打电话
Now, just, uh, tell me where we're going to be and I'll make some calls.
我能搞到7.5折
I think I can get the fourth one for free.
快速问答 假肢 能不能接受
Quick question. Prosthetic arm. Deal breaker?
- 巴尼... - 在你说不之前 想下 这可是有赠品的
- Barney, there is... - Before you say no, it has attachments.
本字幕由YYeTs美剧字幕组原创翻译制作
仅供学习交流之用 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
欢迎访问YYeTs美剧论坛进行交流 www.YYETS.com
Subtitles : Willow's Team
老爸老妈的浪漫史
第二季 第十九集
Transcript : Raceman
翻译：    不二色的鱼        校对：     雨亦奇
www.forom.com
后期：     oliver0951      字幕监制：  叶煦
我知道你是为马修的派对想点子
Look, I know you have some stuff planned for Marshall's bachelor party,
- 但他真的不想要脱衣舞 - 不  他想要
- but he really doesn't want strippers. - Yes, he does.
- 他跟我说他不要 - 他跟我说他要
- Uh, well, he told me he doesn't. - Uh, well, he told me he does.
- 什么时候 - 每时每刻
- When? - Every minute of every day
当他骨子里的兽性 挣破他道德约束的囚笼
as his inner animal thrashes against the cage of his own puritanical upbringing.
难道你们不喜欢裸女
Or do you guys not like naked girls.
当然喜欢
Um, we love naked girls.
她们可是世上最棒的
They're one of the best things in the world.
依次为...裸女  民主
It goes... naked girls, democracy,
永不低头中 猴子给那家伙竖中指
the scene in Every Which Way But Loose where the monkey gives a guy the finger.
- 我们只是不想要你找来的舞娘 - 什么?难道我找来的姑娘不够辣?
- We just don't like your naked girls. - What, my girls aren't hot enough?
斯图尔特派对上 的那个舞娘只有15岁
I mean, all right, fine, the stripper at Stuart's bachelor party was a 15.
- 她15岁? - 不  15点  在21点中的点数
- She was 15? - No, a 15. Like in blackjack.
我在犹豫到底要不要出手
As in, not sure whether you'd hit it?
- 真的 - 太好了
- Exactly. - Nice.
这对马修很重要 答应我  不搞脱衣舞
This is important to Marshall. So, promise me, no strippers.
好吧  我保证
All right, I promise.
- 我很认真 - 我也很认真  不会有脱衣舞
- I'm serious. - So am I. No strippers.
再说一次  别眨眼睛
Now say it without winking.
不会有脱衣舞
No strippers.
- 你眨眼了 - 不  我没有
- You just winked. - No I didn't.
我们开着一辆 租来的凯迪拉克然后出发
So, when the day arrived, we all climbed into a rented Escalade and set out.
现在的单身汉派对通常构成如下
Now, every bachelor party is usually made up of the same stock characters.
新郎
You've got the groom...
伴郎
the best man...
- 只会陈词滥调的家伙 - 死囚漫步(电影片名)
- the guy who speaks only in clichs... - Dead man walking!
在派对开始便消失
...the guy who disappears at the beginning of the night
直到结束才出现的家伙
and doesn't show up again until the end.
去旅馆前先玩玩21点怎么样
All right, who's up for a little blackjack before we check in.
不...不...不...
- No, no, no. - None for me.
到时候旅馆见了
See you guys back at the room, then.
当然  还有巴尼
And, of course, well... Barney.
- 每个单身汉派对都有一个巴尼这样的人 - 这是什么
Every bachelor party has a Barney. Oh, what's this?
这车还有DVD?这么说...
This car has a DVD player? You mean,
我们可以一路上看看A片了
we could have been watching these pornos the whole time?
这是高清格式的
- Yeah. - This one's in HD.
这是高清+高清的
This one's in H-double-D. Oh!
同一个晚上 莉莉阿姨也有一个单身女子派对
That same night, aunt Lily was having a wedding shower.
罗宾手持礼物出场
And Robin showed up gift in hand.
关于这礼物还有个有趣的故事
Funny story about that gift.
我为莉莉准备的礼物 看看怎么样
Hey, Barney, check out what I got Lily for her shower.
很是性感火辣  你行吗
It's kind of racy. Think you can handle it?
十倍于此我都受得了 没问题
Uh, I've been in a ten-way. So, yeah.
是透明装
- It's kind of see-through. - Whoa, ho ho!
你开玩笑吧 你知道这个什么年代最适合?
You weren't kidding! You know when you should give that to her?
1850年
1850.
这是她告别单身的派对
Robin, it's her bridal shower!
她所有的朋友都会出席 喝酒狂欢
All her friends are gonna be there, they're going to be drinking.
你该送她一份大胆的 过火的礼物
You need to get her something daring, something outrageous.
那你觉得我该送她什么
Well, what do you think I should get her?
第八大道上有一家店专门卖...
There's a store on Eighth Avenue that specializes in--
要怎么说呢
how to put this delicately?--
供人寻欢作乐的人造阳具 装电池的...
uh, battery-powered, adult- recreational fake penises.
于是罗宾阿姨来到 第八大道的那家店里
And so Aunt Robin went to a store on Eighth Avenue,
买了一个装电池的 供人寻欢作乐的...
and a battery-powered, adult-recreational...
跟你们说这个不大合适 我们快进...
Well, it was something inappropriate. And we're back in.
罗宾
Robin!
真高兴你能来
I'm so glad you're here.
过来  我要把你介绍给大家
Come in, I want you to meet everybody.
这是我祖母罗伊斯 这是我阿姨佛罗伦斯
Robin, this is my Grandma Lois and my Aunt Florence.
亲爱的  见到你真高兴
Oh, lovely to meet you, dear.
她们筹办了今天晚上的派对
They put this whole party together.
跟我想象中有些不一样 但很温馨
It's different from what I expected, but lovely.
真的很温馨
Lovely.
这儿居然还有小孩!
And oh, look, there are little kids here!
是我的表妹
Yeah, my cousins.
我忘了点东西 在别的地方了  所以我得...
Listen, I, uh, I forgot something somewhere so I'm going to just go...
罗宾  这是我妈妈杰尼斯
Robin, this is my mom, Janice.
真高兴今天终于可以见到你
Oh, honey. I'm so glad to finally meet you.
我也是  久闻您的大名
Me too. I, I've heard so much about you.
我也一直听说你 让我帮你拿礼物吧
Me, too. Oh, here. Let me take your gift.
让我猜猜是什么 一个迷你食品加工机?
Can I guess what it is? Is it a, a, a mini food processor?
- 不 - 不是吗?
- No. - No? Oh.
给我点提示吧  是什么颜色的?
Oh, give me a hint. What color is it?
黑色
Black.
我想我得等到 礼物拆开才知道是什么了
Well, I guess I'm just going to have to wait and see!
罗宾
- Oh, great. - Robin...
这是我堂妹玛格丽特
This is my Cousin Margaret.
终于有跟我们一样年纪的了
Oh, finally, someone our own age!
我应该介绍你为玛格丽特堂妹 还是玛格丽特修女?
Wait, do I introduce you as "Cousin Margaret" or "Sister Margaret?"
我要到下个月才正式成为修女
Well, I'm not officially confirmed as a nun until next month
我也不想催那位大人物
and I don't want to tick off the Big Guy,
所以现在还是叫"表妹"好了
so let's stick with "Cousin" for now.
连上帝都在  太好了
God's watching. Excellent!
他们拍这部片子可以花了大钱了
Man, they spent a lot of money on this porno.
摩根・弗里曼? 每部电影都看得到这老兄
Whoa-- Morgan Freeman? Man, that guy's in everything.
我拿错碟了 这是《彗星撞地球》
Aw, man, I grabbed the wrong Deep Impact!
别换碟  这电影不错
No, leave it in, it's a good movie.
可是伙计 这部电影没有做爱
But, dude, there's no sex in it.
就像婚姻  不是吗
Yeah, just like marriage. Huh? Right?
试试这个 别问我从哪弄的
Oh, oh, hey, check this out! Don't ask how,
但我给大家搞到5根洛可比亚诺牌
but I procured for us five loco-bueno,
手工卷制 绝对违法的古巴雪茄
hand-rolled, highly illegal Cubans.
我不是开玩笑 抽这玩意儿都能让你蹲大狱
Seriously, you could go to jail for smoking these things.
婚姻就像监狱  对不?
Marriage is like jail! Right, fellas?!
但在监狱  你至少还能做爱
But at least in jail, you get to have sex!
但在抵达A.C前 我们还不能享用这些宝贝
But we're not lighting these babies up, till we get to the A.C.
A.C?
A.C.?
大西洋城 跟上我们的思路 布莱德
Um, Atlantic City. Try to keep up, Brad.
我们不是去大西洋城
We're not going to Atlantic City.
等等  布莱德
Just a second, Brad.
- Hi. - Hi.
我们仍然是去大西洋城  是吧?
We're still going to Atlantic City, right?
我没告诉你吗  计划变了 我们去福克斯伍德
Oh, did I not tell you? Yeah, we switched it. We're going to Foxwoods.
福克斯伍德?
Foxwoods?
但我已经让脱衣舞娘 在旅馆里等着了
But I've got an ipperstray waiting in tlanticaay itycay.
他妈的去福克斯伍德干什么
What the heck's in Foxwoods?
我们有5张波平斯基跟萨拉扎 重赛的第三排座位票
Well, we've got five third row seats to the Popinski-Salazar rematch.
他们留了一张赌桌给我们
They've set aside our very own craps table,
我还在Connelly's订了一个包厢
and I reserved a private room for us at Connelly's,
在那里我们将尽情 享用重达102盎司的牛排
where the five of us are going to be sharing a 102-ounce steak
牛排是我在网上订的
from a cow that I picked out on the Internet.
很好  今晚就被你糟蹋了
- Yeah. - Great. The night's ruined.
抱歉  巴尼 这只是个善良的谎言
Sorry, Barney. It was an honest mistake.
完美的夜晚正等着我们
This is going to be great!
暴吃牛排  拳击 大把的赌博烧钱
Meat, violence, throwing money down the toilet.
烧美元得一分  烧其他货币不得分
America-- one; every other country-- zero.
伙计们  谢谢
- Thanks, guys. - Yeah.
你还好吗  巴尼
You okay, Barney?
你想我说什么 泰德  你赢了
What can I say, Ted? You won.
Hi.
你是个可悲又可怜的输家
You one... sad, pathetic loser.
跟宝贝打个招呼吧
Boys, say hello to Treasure.
嗨 宝贝
Hi, Treasure.
- 真不敢相信你居然这么做了 - 我应该的
- I can't believe that you did this. - I had to.
- 我是你的伴郎 - 泰德才是我伴郎
- I'm your best man. - Ted's my best man.
你做了决定  这很好
You've yet to make a decision and that's fine.
但作为你的未来伴郎 我有义务确保你参加在单身汉派对
But as your best-man-to-be, it's my job to make sure at your bachelor party
欣赏女郎在怀特斯奈克的 音乐声中边脱边舞
you see a woman take her clothes off while dancing to Whitesnake's "Here I Go Again."
好吧  随便你  但快点结束好吗
All right, fine, but... let's make it fast, all right.
比赛一个小时后开始 我们可不想错过
The fight starts in an hour we don't want to miss it.
只是个姑娘脱衣服 这要得了多少时间
It's a girl taking her clothes off. How long can it take?
没你想的那么简单
It's a bit more complicated than that.
我要两个接地插座 一个干净的大壶装满热水
I need two grounded sockets, a large sterile pot filled with hot water
并且你们都得签署这个证书
and you all need to sign these releases.
一个打蛋器 谢谢西尔维亚姨妈
An egg beater! Aw, thank you, Aunt Sylvia!
还是无绳的  我很喜欢
I love that it's cordless.
至少我的也不需要电线
Well, at least I got that part right.
你们的礼物都太有创意了
All of these gifts are so thoughtful.
莉莉?
Lily?
我要你现在看着我  听我的心声
I need you to look at me right now and read my mind.
- 我的上帝  你听见了 - 是的
- Oh, my God! You're hearing me! - Yeah!
抱歉派对有点无聊  你怎么了
Sorry this party's so boring. What's up?
不要打开我的礼物
Do not open my gift.
看见我的动作了吗
See what I'm doing here?
我先看看礼物  再回头看你
I'm looking over at the gift, then back at you,
接着摇头  "不要"
and I'm shaking my head, "no."
礼物  你...不要?
Gift. You. No.
懂了吗?
Are you getting that?
完全了解
I totally got it.
给你这个
Here you go.
莉莉说你正是每月的那几天
Lily said it was your time of the month.
不客气
You're welcome.
你要做什么
What are you doing?
只是...把礼物重新摆放一下 看上去有些摇摇欲坠
Oh, just, um... rearranging the gifts. The pile looked a bit precarious. So...
别担心  我会看着的
Oh, don't worry, I'll keep an eye on it.
那好  你来吧
Great. You do that.
你他妈一定会是个好修女的
You're gonna make a damn good nun.
此后数年  每当罗宾讲到这件事
As many times as Robin told this story over the years,
她都无法合理的 解释她接下来的行为
she would never quite be able to explain the logic of her next move.
这是脱衣秀还是Kiss组合的演唱会啊
Is this a strip show or a Kiss concert?
嘘  她正要开始呢
Shh! She's starting.
请关掉手机传呼机 释放你们内心的狂野激情吧
Please turn off your cell phones, pagers and sense of shame.
帅哥们  舒服的躺着 尽情享受吧
All right, boys. Lie back, get comfortable, and enjoy the show.
我不能向你们描述演出的具体内容
Of course there's no way I'm telling you about her show.
所以跳过这一小段
- So, let's skip ahead a little. - Ow!
我的天  你还好吗
Oh my God, are you all right?
不  我不好 你这蠢货  我脚折了!
No, I am not all right, you idiot. My ankle is broken!
送我去医院
Take me to the hospital!
可我们还有比赛的门票
Um, actually, we have tickets.
这一切全拜你所赐
You know what? Thanks a lot, Barney.
她一早就说过
She told you at the beginning of the show
当她在弹力球上的时候 别碰喷雾机
not to use the smoke machine when she's on the hippity hop.
现在我将不得不 在医院继续我的单身派对
Now I'm going to have to spend the rest of my bachelor party in a hospital.
对了 我们去看她的X光片
Well, hey, maybe we'll get to see her X-rays.
终极脱衣秀
The ultimate strip show.
- X片 不如说是三X片 - 给我闭嘴
- X-rays. More like triple X-rays. - Just stop.
哪边是医院出口?
Which exit is the hospital?
如果她没出事多少
What if she doesn't make it to the hospital?
巴尼  冷静
Barney, please calm down.
也许我们该把她丢进沙漠
Maybe we should just take her to the desert,
活埋  然后彻底撇清这件事
bury her and wash our hands of this whole thing!
帅哥  你怎么了
Dude, what is the matter with you?
我只是想让马修知道 作为他的伴郎...
I'm just trying to illustrate to Marshall that as his best man...
你不是我的伴郎
You're not my best man.
作为他的伴郎
As his best man,
我会帮他把妓女活埋在沙漠里
I would help him bury a hooker in the desert.
我不是妓女
I'm not a hooker.
你不是我的伴郎
And you're not my best man.
你毁了我的派对
You've ruined my bachelor party.
实在搞不懂 当我拒绝你的提议时
I don't know why you wouldn't just
你怎么就不听从我呢
listen to me when I said I didn't want this.
比赛十分钟前开始了 也许我们该听听广播
Well, the fight started ten minutes ago. Maybe-maybe we should listen.
多么精彩的比赛啊
Oh, Doctor, what a fight!
最后这一击将在 以后为人们所津津乐道
That knockout will be talked about for years to come!
今晚在场的所有人
Anyone lucky enough to be in the arena tonight
将有幸成为拳坛历史的见证者
just witnessed boxing history in the making!
太感谢你了  玛格丽特
Thank you so much, Margaret.
真不敢相信这个 十字架是你亲手刻的
I can't believe you carved that crucifix yourself.
你太有才了
So talented.
Didn't think you could carve.
给你
For you. Oh.
这是...
And this one's from...
- 路易斯奶奶的礼物 - 亲爱的  等等
- Grandma Lois. - Oh. No, wait, darling.
在你打开它之前  我有话要说
Before you open this, I-I want to say a few words.
我得事先声明
Okay, something you need to know.
路易斯奶奶以为这是 她送给她孙女的古董缝纫机
Grandma Lois thought she was giving her granddaughter an antique sewing machine.
继续我们的故事
And we're back in.
这个手控的小玩意 在我们家世代相传
Honey, this handy little device has been in our family for generations.
我用过  你曾祖母用过
I used it, your great grandmother used it.
太祖母没用过这个 但她有一个差不多的东西
Now, her mother didn't use this one, but she used one just like it.
话说回来  它们都是木制品
Of course, back then, they were made out of wood.
我想在那之前 人们只能靠自己的双手来解决
And, uh, I guess before that, you just had to do it by hand.
请把酒递o我一下
Would you pass the wine, please?
不...
No.
马修
Hey, Marshall,
既然你来这了 你可以去停尸房
while we're here, you may as well go down to the morgue and
钻进停尸的柜子 因为婚姻就是这样
climb into a drawer, 'cause that's what marriage is like.
你们同意吗
Can I get an amen?
- 斯图尔特  你跟你老婆还好吧? - 不好
- Is everything all right at home, Stuart? - No.
腿断了
It's broken.
该死  这真糟糕 我不能丢掉这份工作
Oh, damn it, this is bad. I really can't lose this job.
我女儿就要开学了 可我家那口子...
My daughters are about to start school, and my fianc? well...
自打从伊拉克回来 他就只知道喝酒
ever since he got back from Iraq, pretty much all he does is drink.
我想过要离开他  但...
I think about leaving him, but...
我不想女儿们像我一样 在没有父亲的环境长大
I don't want my girls growing up without a dad like I did.
我不愿让她们有那样的经历
I don't want them to know what that's like.
- 该表演了? - 你有毛病?
- So, show time? - What is the matter with you?
她腿断了
Her ankle's broken.
我非常清楚 她通常以就座或仰卧的姿势
I know for a fact that the second half of her act
进行下半段的表演
takes place largely in a seated or supine position.
是的
Oh, that's true.
宝贝  别为演出发愁
Treasure, please, don't worry about the show.
我们会很内疚
Uh, we'd feel bad.
你什么意思
What does that mean?
我是说  你又不是妓女
No. We just mean, uh, you're off the hook.
你不是非得这么干
You don't have to do it.
我不是非得这么干? 你算什么东西
I don't have to do it? Well, guess what?
我知道我该干什么 我做这行是因为我擅长
I know I don't have to do it. I do it because I am good at it.
我不需要你的同情怜悯
Look, I don't need your pity.
我只是想让你欣赏到精彩的表演 因为你要结婚了!
All I want to do is give you a great show because you're getting married!
这是很过分的要求吗 这让你很不便吗
Is that so much to ask? Is that such a major inconvenience?!
这是个错误
Oh, that is wrong.
错得太离谱了
Oh, that's just so wrong.
医生有嘱咐她保持高抬腿
Well, the doctor did say for her to keep it elevated.
我还是个小姑娘的时候
When I was a girl,
我母亲就教我和我妹妹如何使用它
my mother taught me and my sister to use it.
我们常常比赛看谁做得更快
We used to have contests to see who could finish faster.
全家人都围在一起看 相当激动人心
It was so exciting. The whole family would gather around to watch.
而我新婚的时候
And when I was a new bride,
多亏了它  我才在 你们祖父远征朝鲜的
this is what kept me buzy
那些漫漫长夜里不那么寂寞难耐
all those long nights when your grandfather was in Korea.
说到你们祖父
And speaking of your grandfather,
尽管我不觉得他会向谁承认  但...
though I don't think he'd care to admit this to any of his army buddies, but...
每隔一阵他就会拿它出来...
he'd have a go at it every once in a while.
他喜欢这个
And he enjoyed it.
打开看看  亲爱的
Oh, open it up, sweetie.
愿它给你欢愉 就像它曾带给我的
May this give for you as much joy as it's brought me.
奶奶...
Grandma, um...
Wow.
拿出来啊  亲爱的 我想教你怎么用
Well, take it out, honey. I want to show you how to use it.
不  不  别拿出来
Okay, no, no! Don't take it out.
莉莉  那不是你奶奶的礼物 是我的
Lily, that's not your grandma's gift. It's mine.
我很慌张  我很尴尬 所以我偷换了礼物上的卡片
I panicked, and I switched the cards because I was embarrassed.
这到底是什么
Well, what is it?
这跟《欲望都市》里 米兰达送夏洛特的一样
It's just like the one Miranda gave to Charlotte on Sex and the City.
我喜欢那个剧 我一直看TBS的《欲望都市》
Oh, I love that show. I always watch it on TBS.
确实值得一看  你就是莎曼莎
Oh, you would. You're such a Samantha!
我是凯利  而你是莎曼莎
Oh, I'm a Carrie! You're a Samantha!
然后那一晚变成了另一种的不爽
And then the night became a whole new kind of uncomfortable.
- 我该上哪儿去买这个呢 - 妈
- So where do I get one of these? - Mom!
伙计  烂透了的表演  是吧
Man, what a show, huh?
瞧她那恶心的姿势 整个儿都粘在你身上
She did some disgusting stuff. Really sticks with you.
我不吃了
I may be done eating.
我也是
Me, too.
我是说永远
I mean, like, forever.
我也是
Me, too.
我想我老婆
I miss my wife.
吃完饭大家就聊聊 最喜欢哪部分的表演
Hey, let's go around the table and say what our favorite part was.
我喜欢有打字机的那一段
Mine was that thing with the typewriter.
尽管她有很多拼写错误 但这不影响...
I mean, she made some spelling mistakes, but still.
你们这些家伙 都叫  "巴尼  把烟灭掉"
Ooh, and you guys were all, "Barney, put out the cigar!
"这是无烟室" 我说  "不  这可是古巴烟草"
It's a non-smoking room!" And I was all, "Hell, no, this is a Cuban!"
当然  我最后还是把烟灭了
Of course, eventually, I did put it out.
我灭了吗
Did I put it out?
我灭了
I put it out.
我灭了吗
Did I put it out?
我灭了
I put it out.
我灭了吗
Did I put it out?
火灾并不严重
It was a small fire,
还不至于让整个旅馆的人被疏散
not even big enough to force an evacuation of the hotel,
但却足够糟糕到让我们被赶出去
but definitely big enough to get us kicked out,
因此提前结束马修的单身汉派对
and bring Marshall's bachelor party to an early end.
那是...?
Is that...?
正是
It is.
嗨  伙计们
Hey, guys.
战况如何
How was the fight?
你们在这儿干?单身汉派对?
Hey, what are you guys doing here? What happened to the bachelor party?
我们错过了拳击比赛 晚饭也被毁了
We missed the fight, dinner was ruined,
我们在医院呆了半个晚上 并且被旅馆赶了出来
we spent half the night in the hospital,and got kicked out of the hotel.
你觉得发生什么了
What do you think happened?
- 巴尼 - 巴尼
- Barney. Barney.
我只是想做个称职的伴郎
Hey, I was just trying to be a good best man.
你知道怎样才是称职的伴郎?
You know what a best man does, Barney?
他得紧密团结在 以新郎为核心的周围
He does what the groom wants.
可你都只是按照 你的意愿做你想做的
But all you ever think about is what you want, what's best for you.
伴郎?
Best man?
我现在都不确定是否要请你参加我的婚礼
I'm not even sure I'm inviting you to the wedding at this point.
你不会吧
You don't mean that.
我干吗要请你 你甚至都不希望我们结婚
Why should I invite you? You don't even want us to get married.
巴尼不是那样的人
That's not true.
莉莉  别说了
Lily, don't.
什么
What?
很抱歉  巴尼
I'm sorry, Barney.
那是去年夏天我们分手时候的事
It happened last summer when we were broken up.
伙计们  聊什么呢
Hey, what are you guys talking about?
- 莉莉... - 我得走了
- Lily. - Ah, I got to go.
纽华克机场  谢谢
Newark Airport, please.
巴尼  你怎么来了
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Barney, what are you doing here?
难以置信真的是你 进来  快请坐...
I can't believe it's really you. Come in, have a seat.
要喝茶吗  我知道公寓很小
Do you want some tea? I know the apartment's small,
但对我已经足够了 给你看看我的画
but I don't need much space. Let me show you some of my paintings.
是我至今为止最好的作品
I think it's some of my best work ever.
如果你要说这些那就闭嘴吧
Just stop it.
莉莉  你得回家 你跟马修心心相印
Lily, you have to come home. You and Marshall belong together.
你们俩
The two of you
是天作之合而许多人 却有缘无份  只能抱憾终身
have something that most people search their whole lives for and never find.
我知道你爱他 如果你知道 他现在是怎样的颓废萎靡
I know you love him, and if you knew what he was going through right now,
你绝对在这儿呆不下去
you wouldn't be here for one more second.
我给你买了回去的机票
I bought you a ticket home.
马修是我认识的最好的人
Marshall is one of the best people I know,
迟早别人也会发现这点
and it won't be long until someone else realizes that,
那时你就会永远失去他了
and you'll lose him forever.
只是假设  我都难以接受
I can't stand the thought of that happening,
可我也不能总守在他身边 把觊觎他的小妞都拐走
and I cannot keep stealing chicks from him forever.
千万  千万别告诉 别人我来过  我会抵死否认
Never, ever tell anyone I was here. I will deny it tooth and nail.
我从没来过
This trip never happened.
如果你在登机前 有三个小时空闲  你要怎么打发?
Hey, if you had three hours to kill before your flight, what would you do--
是逛监狱岛?还是渔人码头? (注:都是旧金山的旅游景点)
Alcatraz or Fisherman's Wharf?
这是真的吗
You really did that?
我认为巴尼是你真正的好朋友
Marshall, I think Barney's your best man.
Yeah.
是  他是的
Yes, he is.
知道了吧  莉莉 这就是为什么我不...
See, Lily? This is why I didn't...
- 真的吗 - 真的
- Really? - Really.
真...
Real...
瞧瞧你那表情啊  你输了
In your face, loser!
别激动  泰德 也仍然是我的伴郎
Take it easy, all right. Ted's still my best man, too.
你们俩都是伴郎
You guys are co-best men.
是的  我们都是伴郎
Right. Yes, we're both best man.
不  正确的说  你们
No, um, seriously. You guys are co-best men.
当然
Of course.
真不敢相信你送我这个
I can't believe you got me this.
我只是想开个玩笑 如果你不喜欢我可以拿去退
Oh, I only did it as a joke. I can return it for you you want.
不 不 不用了 拿去退太麻烦了
Oh, no, it's okay. You don't have to go all the way back down there.
我可以把它放一边
I'll, I'll just throw it away.
这样的话
Well, I mean,
如果你要把它放一边 还不如让我拿走
if you were going to throw it away, maybe I'll take it
下次谁再请我参加单身聚会 我就不用买了
in case I get invited to another wedding shower.
这可是让人瞠目结舌的礼物
It's a great gag gift.
是  这东西很有意思
Yeah, it's really funny.
你猜谁会被它吓得最厉害
You know who would get a kick out of it?
马修
Marshall.
所以  也许我该把它留着
So, so maybe I'll just hold on to it.
要是马修知道我送这个给你 我会很难为情的
I would be embarrassed if Marshall found out that I bought it for you,
- 所以我最好拿走 - 罗宾  给我
- so I'd better just take it. - Robin, leave it.